Arthur Frank Wertheim Papers, 1862-2005 (bulk 1895-1929) MS 438
University of Arizona Library Special Collections
Arthur Frank Wertheim Papers 1862-2005 (bulk 1895-1929)
MS 438
Wertheim, Arthur Frank, 1935-
Printed material and photographs, 1862-2005 (bulk 1895-1929). The bulk of the material is photocopies of printed materials, primarily newspaper and journal articles, collected by Wertheim while researching the writing of his book, Vaudeville Wars. The collection contains information on many aspects of Vaudeville including; performers, theater and circuit owners and managers, theater and circuit management and organization, professional associations and unions, theater buildings, legal activities, and the history of vaudeville as an industry. Photographs contain images of people, organizations and places associated with vaudeville.
14 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None
University of Arizona Libraries Special Collections, Vaudeville collection, MS 421
University of Arizona Libraries Special Collections, Goelet Family papers, MS 432
University of Arizona Libraries Special Collections, Kathryn Beals papers, MS 440
Biographical Note
Arthur Frank Wertheim was born December 22, 1935, in New York, N.Y. Son of Albert (a stockbroker) and Ruth (Weisberg) Wertheim. He married Carol J. Youngberg, February 4, 1972; they have one son, Jason Albert.
Arthur Frank Werthheim received his B.A. in 1957 from Yale University. He then went to New York University where he got his M.A. in 1967 and his Ph.D. in 1970. From 1971-78 he was an assistant professor of American Studies at the University of Southern California, Los Angeles. Arthur then went to the University of Indonesia, Jakarta where he was a Fulbright professor of American studies for one year, 1978-79.
He has written several books on 20th Century American culture, including The New York Little Renaissance and Radio Comedy. He has also co-edited with Barbara Bair three volumes of the Papers of Will Rogers and edited Will Rogers at the Ziegfeld Follies and American Popular Culture. He was a former professor of American History at the University of Southern California and other universities, as well as an administrator at the University of California, Los Angeles. His awards include a Fulbright grant to teach at the University of Indonesia.
This Collection is organized into 9 series.
Series I: Managers/Owners/Theatres, 1851-1998
Series II: Unions, 1895-1994 (bulk 1895-1939)
Series III: Legal, 1914-1939 (bulk 1914-1920)
Series IV: Performers, 1894-2003 (bulk 1905-1960)
Series V: Pre-Vaudeville, 1862-1991 (bulk 1862-1929)
Series VI: Circuits
Subseries 1: Orpheum Circuit, 1883-2005 (bulk 1883-1940)
Subseries 2: Keith-Albee Circuit, 1885-2005 (bulk 1885-1930)
Series VII: Subject Files, 1884-2004 (bulk 1884-1929)
Series VIII: News and Events, 1895-1929
Series IX: Photographs, 1895-1928
Printed material and photographs, 1862-2005 (bulk 1895-1929). The bulk of the material is photocopies of printed material, primarily newspaper and journal articles, collected by Wertheim while researching the writing of his book, Vaudeville Wars. The collection contains information on many aspects of Vaudeville including performers, theater and circuit owners and managers; theater and circuit management and organization; professional associations and unions; theater buildings; legal activities; and the history of vaudeville as an industry. Photographs contain images of people, organizations and places associated with vaudeville.
Actors – Labor Unions – United States.; Actors' Equity Association.; Albee, Edward, 1928-; Associated Actors and Artists of America.; Beck, Martin, 1868?-1940.; Considine, John W., 1863-1943.; Entertainers -- United States.; Fox, William, 1879-1952.; Golden, George Fuller, 1868-1912.; Hammerstein, Oscar, 1895-1960.; Hammerstein, Oscar, 1846-1919.; Hammerstein, William.; Keith, B. F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1846-1914.; Labor Unions – United States.; Leavitt, M. B. (Michael B.), 1843-1935.; Loew, Marcus, 1870-1927.; Miner, Henry Clay, 1865 or 6-1950.; Morris, William, 1873-1932.; Music-halls (Variety-theaters, cabarets, etc.).; Pantages Circuit of Vaudeville Theatres.; Pantages, Alexander, 1876-1936.; Pastor, Tony.; Poli, Sylvester Z.; Proctor, F. F., (Frederick Freeman), 1851-1929.; Radio-Keith-Orpheum Corporation.; Shubert Brothers Archive – Lee, Jacob, & Sam.; Sullivan, Timothy D., 1863-1913.; Theater management – United States.; Theaters -- United States.; Theatrical managers -- United States.; United Booking Offices of America (Organization).; Variety (New York, N.Y.).; Revues.; Vaudeville; Vaudeville – Employees – Labor Unions – United States.; Vaudeville—History.; White Rats of America.; Williams, Percy G., 1857-1923.
- Series I: Managers/Owners/Theaters, 1851-1998
  Series note: This series is arranged alphabetically by last name.
  It contains photocopies from various sources of information related to individuals, as a manager, owner, or of various theaters between 1851 - 1998.
  - Anderson, Max C., 1860 or 1-1915 1900- 1922, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Casey, Pat, (P.J.), d.1962.1908-09, 1914, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chase, P. B., (Plimpton B.), 1860-1938.1902, 1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Considine, John W., 1863-1943.1905-1910, 1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cordray, John F.1851- 1895, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cort, John, 1859-1929.1891-1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cox, George Barnsdale, 1853-1916.1912, 1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Davis, Harry.1904-1910 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Erlanger, A. L., (Abraham Lincoln), 1860-1930.1908- 1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fox, William, 1879-1952.1910- 1941, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Frohman, Charles, 1860-1915.undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fynes, J. Austin, (James Austin), b.1859 or 601898-1905, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Grauman, Sid, 1880-1950.1909, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hammerstein, Arthur, 1872-1955.1930, 1955, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, 1846-1919.1906, 1919, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hammerstein, Oscar, 1895-1960. Dissertation by Carroll, John F. c.1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hammerstein, William (Willie), 1874-1914.1913-1919, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hammerstein’s Olympia Theatre.1895, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hammerstein’s Victoria Theatre.1898- 1934, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hart, Max, 1874-1950.1918-1928, 1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hooley, Richard M. (Uncle Dick), 1822-1893.1893 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jacobs, H. R. (Henry). 1886- 1915 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Kernan, James.1905 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Klaw, Marc, 1858-1936.1908, 1936, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Levitt, Michael B., 1843-1935.1887- 1920, 1940, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Loew, Marcus, 1870-1927.1910- 1927, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Loew, Sullivan & Considine War.1911-1915 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Loew’s Theatres.1910-1976, 1983, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miner, Henry Clay, (Harry), 1865 or 6-1950.1842-1900 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Miner’s Theatres.1876-1913, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Moore, James.1898, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Morris, William, (Bill), 1873-1932. (1)1908- 1953, 1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Morris, William, (Bill), 1873-1932. (2) 1908- 1932, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Morrison, Patsy.undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pantages, Alexander, 1876-1936.1907 - 1936, 1960-1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pantages Circuit of Vaudeville Theatres.1909- 1929, 1966-1971, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Pastor, Antonio, (Tony), 1836-1911.1899-1911, 1931, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Poli, Sylvester Z., 1859-1937.1860-1920 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Poli, Sylvester Z. Dissertation by: Oberdeck, Kathryn Jane, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Poli Theatres.1906, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Proctor, F.F., (Frederick Freeman), 1851-1929.1901-1953, 1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Proctor Enterprises.1888-1905, 1912, 1986-1987, 1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Proctor’s Fifth Ave. Theatre.1873- 1906, 1938, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Proctor’s Newark Theatre (Park Place).1898 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Proctor’s Pleasure Palace Theatre.1895- 1903, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Proctor’s Theatre 23rd Street.1891-1904, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Proctor’s Theatre, Troy, NY, 4th Street.1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Rhinock, Joseph L., d. 1926.1926, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Rothafel, Samuel Lionel, (Roxy), 1882-1936.1927, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Scribner, Samuel A., d. 1941.1908, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Shea, Mauarice A., (Mort), 1880-1940.1940, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Shea, Michael, 1859-1934.1934, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Shea, P.F., (Pat).1899, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Shubert Brothers Archive (Lee, Jacob, Sam).1905- 1925, 1989- 1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Shubert, Lee, 1875-1953.1953, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Shubert, Lee & Albee/Keith—Correspondence.1910-1922 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Sullivan and Considine Theatre Circuit.1886-1914, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sullivan, Timothy D., (Big Tim), 1862-1913.1896- 1914, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sun, Gus, (Gustave Ferdinand), 1868-1959.1907 - 1939, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Theatres, Atlantic City.1980 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Theatres, Boston.1982-1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Theatres, Chicago Includes Auditorium.1883-1906, 1972, 1986-87, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Theatres, Hippodrome, New York City.1904- 1912, 1972- 1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Theatres, Los Angeles.1982-83, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Theatres, Miscellanous.1895-1913,1971- 1987, 1989- 1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Theatres, New York City.1892-1910, 1973, 1986-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Theatres, Radio City Music Hall.undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Theatres, San Francisco.1903-1907, 1983-1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Theatres, Time Square.1977- 1992 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Theatres, Ziegfeld.1927, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Williams, Percy G., 1857-1923.1857-1929 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Williams Alhambra Harlem Theatre.1904, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Series II: Unions, 1895-1994 (bulk 1895-1939)
  Series note: This series is arranged alphabetically by name.
  It contains photocopies from various sources of information related to the history of Actors Union’s including primary leaders of a union between 1895 - 1994.
  - Actors Equity Association.1913- 1924, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Actors National Protective Union.1895-1910 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Associated Actors and Artists of America (Four A’s).1909- 1939, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Associated Actresses of America (Women’s Branch of the White Rats).1907- 1914 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Comedy Club.1906-1914 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Friars Club, Friars National Association, Inc.undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Golden, George Fuller, 1868-1912.1897- 1912 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lights Club of Freeport.undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mountford, Harry, 1871-1950.1920-21, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - National Vaudeville Artists, Inc.1916- 1925, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Silverman, Sime, 1873-1933.1905-1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Variety (Magazine)1905-1956, 1980, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Variety and Vaudeville: Sime Silverman’s influence on the organization of Vaudeville Artists. Dissertation by Lowell Stewart Harris 1994 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - White Rats Actors Union.1901, -1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - White Rats Actors Union—A historical study of the White Rats. Dissertation by Thomas Colley1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - White Rats Actors Union- The White Rats versus The Czars of Vaudeville 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - White Rats Bullentin, 1901.1901 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - White Rats Bullentin, 1902.1902 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Series III: Legal, 1914-1939
  It contains photocopies of Legal documents and correspondence summoned by the court, of the case between the Federal Trade Commission and Vaudeville Managers, Owners and Unions between 1914 – 1920. Also contains photocopies of articles from various newspapers and magazines covering the hearings between 1918 -1920. Includes other legal hearings between 1921-1939.
  - Federal Trade Commission vs. Vaudeville … (1)1914-1920 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Federal Trade Commission vs. Vaudeville … (2)1914-1920 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Federal Trade Commission vs. Vaudeville … (3)1914-1920 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Federal Trade Commission vs. Vaudeville … (4)1914-1920 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Federal Trade Commission vs. Vaudeville … (5)1914-1920 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Federal Trade Commission vs. Vaudeville … News related from Billboard 1918-1920 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Federal Trade Commission vs. Vaudeville News related from New York ‘Clipper’ 1919-1920 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Federal Trade Commission vs. Vaudeville News related from Variety. 1919-1920 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hart vs Keith.1921-1926 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous.1921- 1939 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Senate Hearings – Stock Exchange Practices.1932, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Performers, 1894-2003 (bulk 1905-1960)
  Series note: This series is arranged alphabetically by surname.
  This series contains printed material including entries from encyclopedias and other reference resources, newspaper clippings, journal and magazine articles and book chapters. The information about the performers includes biographical information, performance and work history, research on individual performers or acts, and performers’ impact on vaudeville as an industry. The series contains material from the time of vaudeville as well as material from retrospectives and research done after the end of vaudeville.
  - Allen, Fred1923, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bergere, Valerie1938, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Barrymore, Ethel1958 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bayes, Nora1911-1928, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Burke, Ethel (Billie)1908 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Byers, Chester1910-1916, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bernhardt, Sarahundated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Brice, Fannyundated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Butt, Alfred1908-16, 1962, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Carlisle, Gertie1925 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Carrillo, Leopoldo Antonio (Leo)1906-1909, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Carter, Lincoln J.1926, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Casey, Patrick (Pat)undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Castle, Irene and Vernon1913-1918, 1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Cherry Sisters1934, 1942, 1944, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Chevalier, Albert (Chivvy)undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Clarke, Harry1908, 1923, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Cline, Margaret (Maggie)undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Cohan, George M.1908, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Corbett, James J.1908 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Dausset, Carmen1923-1994, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Davies, Reine1913-1922, 1938, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Dickinson, Richardundated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Dolly Sisters (Rosika (Rose) and Jansci (Jenny) Deutsch)undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - D’orsay, Fifiundated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Dresser, Louise1907-1936, 1965-1994, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Dressler, Marie1908, 1934, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Edwards, Gus (Augustus Edwards Simon)1909-1948, 1979-1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Eltinge, Julian1905-1941, 1976-1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Fogarty, Frank1914, 1925, 1976, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Foy, Eddie (Edwin Fitzgerald)1908, 1914, 1938, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Franklin, Irene1914-1941, 1981-1993, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Friganza, Trixie1908, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Frisco, Joe (Louis Wilson Joseph)undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Green, Burton (James)1922, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Harrigan, Edward1894 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hart, Billy (William Lenhart) and Hart, Marie (Mabel Markwith) 1935, 1983, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hart, Joseph1906-1909, 1921, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hastings, Ned1969 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Held, Anna1908 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Henry, Louise1904-1905, 1970, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Hite, Mabel1908 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Hitchcock, Raymond1908 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Hoffman, Gertrude1910, 1955-1966 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hogan, Ernest1903-1905, 1973, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Hope, Bob2003 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Houdini, Harry1906-1926, 1962-1979, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Janis, Elsie1908, 1932, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Jessel, George1950, 1981, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Jolson, Al1988-1994 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Kajiyama, Tameo1921 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Kalich, Bertha1905-1939, 1971-1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Keaton, Buster1906-1966, 1993-1995, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Kelly, Harry1908 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - La Rue, Grace1914-1956, 1971-1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Latell, Al1924 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Mackaye, Perry Wallace1908 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Mann, Louis1908-1931, 1961-1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Mann, Sam1965-1966, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Marlowe, Julia1908 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - May, George1956 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - McIntyre and Health (James McIntyre and Thomas Health)1925, 1938, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - McKee, Buck1910-1941, 1977-1992, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Mitchell, Abbie1960, 1973, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Montgomery, David1905, 1909-1910, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Morris, Nina1905-1918, 1975, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Morton Family (Sam, Kitty, Clara, Paul)1905-1912 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Morton, James J.1938, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Niblo, Fred1906-1948, 1972-1992, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - North, Bob (Harold Young)1936, 1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Norton, Ruby1906, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Norworth, Jack1930-1959, 1974-1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Rice, Fanny1906-1913, 1936, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Ring, Blanche1908-1916, 1961-1988, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Robinson, Bill (Bojangles)undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Rogers Brothers (Gus and Max Solomon)1908 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Romaine, Martin1917, 1927, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Rooney, Pat1909-1952, 1962-1981, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Roshanara, (Olive Craddock)1926 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Russell, Lillian1922 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Sandow, Eugen1995 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Sargent, Epes Winthropundated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Stahl, Rose1905-1916, 1975, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Stevens, Ashton1951, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Stone, Fred (1)1914-1959, 1975-1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Stone, Fred (2)1914-1959, 1975-1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Tanguay, Eva1908-1947, 1971-1989, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Tiller Girlsundated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Tilley, Vesta1902, 1952, 1956, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Tinney, Frankundated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Trix, Helen1948-1956, 1976, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Tucker, Sophie1945, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Van Alstyne, Egbert1928, 1966-1991, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Van and Schenck (Gus Van and Joe Schenck)1914-1919, 1968, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Walton, Florence1919, 1953, 1975, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Weber and Fields (Joe Weber and Lew Fields)1904, 1908, 1989, 1995, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Williams, Bert (Egbert, Austins)1918-1922, 1981, 1992, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Williams, Gus (Gustave Wilhelm Leweck)1986 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Wills, Natundated (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Series V: Pre-Vaudeville, 1862-1991 (bulk 1862-1929)
  Series note: This series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains printed material including newspaper clippings, advertisements, journal and magazine articles and book chapters. This series includes information on variety theaters, management and circuits, and the transition from variety to vaudeville. Information about other entertainment venues like circuses, medicine shows, concert salons and early museums is also included.
  - Circus shows1890, 1918 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Concert saloons1862-1868, 1968-1991 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Early variety combinations1888-1896, 1907, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Early variety general1888-1915, 1927-1929 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Early variety managers1877-1896, 1906-1912 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Early variety theaters1878-1901, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Medicine shows1889, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Museums1889-1915, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Theatrical Managers Association1889-1894 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Variety and vaudeville1864-1907, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Variety circuits1889-1890, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Variety in New York 1879-1910 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Variety in San Francisco1881-1910 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Series VI: Circuits
  This series is divided into two subseries the Orpheum Circuit and the Keith-Albee Circuit.
  - Subseries 1: Orpheum Circuit,1883-2005 (bulk 1883-1940)
    Subseries note: This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    This series contains printed material including newspaper clippings, advertisements, journal and magazine articles and book chapters. This series includes information on the operations and history of the Orpheum Circuit, Orpheum Circuit executives and employees, management of the theaters, the theater buildings, and interactions with managers’ associations, unions and performers.
    - 19091909, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 19201920 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 19221922, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Ackerman, Charles L.1903, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Beck, Martin1908-1940, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Boston Orpheum theaterundated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Castle, George and Kohl, Charles E. 1883, 1910-1918, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Early Orpheum and Walters, Gustav (1)1893-1899 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Early Orpheum and Walters, Gustav (2)1893-1899 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Death of Gustav Walters1891-1898 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Des Moines Orpheum theater1951, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Denver Orpheum theater1932, 1955, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Duluth Orpheum theater1940-1941, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - General history1907-1928, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Heiman, Marcus1920, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Hopkins, Col. John D. 1895-1909, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Lansburgh, Gustave Albert architect2005 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Lehman, Martin1917 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Los Angeles Orpheum theater1908-1926, 1989-1999, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Memphis Orpheum theaterundated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Meyerfeld, Morris1908, 1935, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Middleton, George1901, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Minneapolis Orpheum theater 1993, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Morrisey, John1897-1903 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - New Orleans Orpheum theater1989, 1993, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Oakland Orpheum theater1907, 1925, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Omaha Orpheum theater1925-1926, 1988, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Orpheum theaters (1)1925 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Orpheum theaters (2)1971-1987, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - San Francisco Orpheum theater1901-1938, 1971-1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Sioux City Orpheum theater1924, 1979, 1982, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Singer, Mort1911, 1920, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - South Bend Orpheum theater1973, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - St. Paul Orpheum theater1975-1981, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Vancouver Orpheum theater1999, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Western circuit vaudeville theaters1897-1900 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Western Vaudeville Manager’s Association1908-1914, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2: Keith-Albee Circuit,1885-2005 (bulk 1885-1930)